activecampaign.com 2013-05-02

# Privacy Policy | ActiveCampaign Help

**Privacy Policy**

Thank you for visiting ActiveCampaign, Inc.’s (“ActiveCampaign”) web site (the “Site”). This privacy policy tells you how we use personal information collected at this Site. Please read this privacy policy before using the Site or submitting any personal information. By using the Site, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy policy. These practices may be changed, but any changes will be posted and changes will only apply to activities and information on a going forward, not retroactive, basis. You are encouraged to review the privacy policy whenever you visit the Site to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used.

**Note:** the privacy practices set forth in this privacy policy are for this [Site](http://www.activecampaign.com/) only. If you link to other web sites, please review the privacy policies posted at those sites.

**Collection of Information**

Your use of the Site does not necessarily require any disclosure of your personally identifiable information; however, we collect personally identifiable information, like names, postal addresses, email addresses, etc., when voluntarily submitted by our visitors.  We or a designated third party may collect payment and credit card information when you contact us or subscribe to any ActiveCampaign services and in connection with processing premium services transactions or other transactions on the Site.

Any third party operator of the Site is responsible for such third party operator’s collection, use and protection of your information.  Additionally, certain third parties may collect personal information from you and share some of the personal information with us.  Additional information about the privacy practices of the companies who collect the data will be provided, including how to opt-out of having these companies use your personal information for purposes unrelated to the services that you have requested. Users can find these options on the websites of the relevant third party operator(s).  These companies and not ActiveCampaign are responsible for the collection and use of your information by these companies.

Access to some services may also require you to use a user name and password, established by you.  Additional information about you may be revealed in any communications you post on message or review boards, which are publicly available to others.  We are not responsible for any communications you or a third party post on the message or review boards.  We may collect personal information as required or permitted by law, or with your consent.  You may withdraw your consent at any time upon reasonable notice, subject to contractual and legal restrictions, but if you do so, we may not be able to provide some of our services.  This information is only used to fulfill your specific request, unless you give us permission to use it in another manner, for example, to add you to one of our mailing lists.

When using the Site or Services, you may import data regarding your clients (“Client Data”).  Such Client Data will not be sold or distributed to a third party without your consent except for in accordance with a sale of any portion of ActiveCampaign to a third party or in accordance with applicable law.

**Cookie/Tracking Technology**

The Site may use cookie and tracking technology depending on the features offered. Cookie and tracking technology is useful for gathering information such as browser type and operating system, tracking the number of visitors to the Site, and understanding how visitors use the Site. Cookies can also help customize the Site for visitors. Personal information cannot be collected via cookies and other tracking technology; however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information. Aggregate cookie and tracking information may be shared with third parties.  You may refuse cookies by changing your internet browser preferences, but doing so may diminish your experience on the websites.  This privacy policy does not cover third parties’ use of cookies.

**Widgets**

You may have the option of downloading and installing “widgets” on your desktop, permitted websites and/or your mobile phone. Widgets are mini-applications programmed to perform a specific function or task that may run on your desktop or may be embedded in websites. For example, we may offer you widgets that have countdowns to various launches. The widgets we offer that are downloaded or installed by you may require you to input personal information, depending on the widget’s function, and may be able to access or use personal information provided by you. Widgets may (i) check for updates automatically and transmit your information to its server and/or engine; (ii) send information entered into or accessed by the widget to its server and/or engine, which may be stored for a temporary period of time; and (iii) be visible to the public if embedded on publicly available webpages (such as social networking webpages), depending on the policies of that website.

**Information use**

We may use your personal information to communicate with you regarding the website, purchases, disputes, payments or inquiries submitted by you. Any Client Data or personal information submitted to us, or our third party service providers or our marketing partners and advertisers acting on our behalf, will not be sold, leased or shared with or to anyone else by us, unless we notify you otherwise in advance, except as follows:

(1) We may share your information, except for Client Data, with our third party service providers or our marketing partners or advertisers, to the extent that they may provide the services you have requested.

(2) We may share your information with our affiliates, employees, contractors, directors and officers.

(3) From time to time, we may offer special promotions (such as a contest or a free subscription to goods and services) on the Site in association with a third party service provider, sponsor or promotional partner. With your consent, we may share your information, except for Client Data, with that third party service provider, sponsor or promotional partner so that it can offer you other special promotions.

(4) If any portion of ActiveCampaign is sold, your information or Client Data may be part of the business assets we transfer. Your information or Client Data also may be disclosed if ActiveCampaign is considering or completes the financing, securitization, insuring, sale, assignment or other transfer of all or part of the company.

(5) We may disclose your information or Client Data to comply with any judicial or governmental subpoenas, warrants or orders. We reserve the right to use, disclose and share your information and Client Data to investigate, prevent or take action with respect to any potential or actual fraud, illegal activities, circumstances which threaten the physical safety of any person, violations of this Site’s Terms of Service or as otherwise required by law.

We may share aggregated demographic information with third parties. Such information does not contain any personal information which may individually identify any person.  We may also use IP addresses for administrative and statistical purposes in order to further understand how people use our Site and to gather demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are only associated with personally identifiable information when it is necessary to verify users’ locations with respect to blackout restrictions for audio and/or video subscription products, as applicable.

**Third-Party Links**

The Site may contain links to other websites operated by unrelated third parties. When you click on these links, you will leave our Site. The privacy practices of third party websites are not our responsibility. Please read the privacy policies of any website that collects personally identifiable information from you. This Privacy Policy applies only to our Site.

**Reviewing Your Personal Information**

You may revise your preferences or amend your personal information by logging onto your account at any time, if one is available. If you want to close your account and have us delete the personal information in it (except for information kept for record-keeping purposes), please contact us at info@activecampaign.com.

**Commitment to Data Security**

Your personally identifiable information is kept secure. Only authorized employees, agents and contractors (who have agreed to keep information secure and confidential) have access to this information. All emails and newsletters from this site allow you to opt out of further mailings.  However, we cannot guarantee that the information we have gathered will never be accessed, disclosed, lost or destroyed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

**Opt-In**

Our registration and order forms allow you to indicate whether or not you would like to receive special offers and promotions from us and/or our partners and sponsors.  Unless you consent to receive such offers and promotions, ActiveCampaign and our respective agents and representatives will use your personal information only to complete the registration or order, or to provide the service or product requested.  If you initially consent to receive such offers, but later change your mind, you can adjust your preferences.

**California Visitors**

If you are a resident of the State of California, under the California Civil Code, you have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third parties to which the company has disclosed personal information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, a company need only provide you with information on how to exercise your rights if it has a privacy policy that allows you to opt-in or opt-out of the use of your personal information by third parties for marketing purposes.

We have elected the latter option; this comprehensive Privacy Policy provides you with details on how to opt-in or opt-out of the use of your personal information by third parties for direct marketing purposes. Therefore, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of all third parties to which we have disclosed your personal information during the preceding year for direct marketing purposes.

If you are a California resident and would like to request information about exercising your third party disclosure rights, please send a request to info@activecampaign.com, and whether you would prefer our response to be sent by e-mail or postal mail.

Please include your e-mail address or your name, street address, city, state and zip code (for our own record-keeping purposes). We will not accept requests by telephone or fax. We are not responsible for notices sent improperly, or which contain incomplete information.

**Visitors From Outside the United States**

The Site’s offices are located in the United States.  If you visit the site from another country, please be aware that information you provide to us or that we obtain as a result of your use of the Site may be processed in and transferred to the United States and will be subject to U.S. law.  U.S. privacy and data protection laws may not be equivalent to the laws in your country of residence.  By using the Site or providing us with your information, you consent to the collection, transfer, storage, and processing of information to and in the United States.

**Part VI.  U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework**

ActiveCampaign complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland.  ActiveCampaign has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view ActiveCampaign’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

ActiveCampaign has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by ActiveCampaign, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at [www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints "http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints") for more information and to file a complaint.

**Children Under the Age of 13**

The Site is not directed or intended for children under 13 years of age.  We do not knowingly collect personal information from individuals under 13 years of age.  If you are under 13 years of age, you should not register or provide personal information on the Site.  If we later obtain actual knowledge that a user is under 13 years of age, we will take steps to remove that user’s personal information from our systems.  If you are the parent or guardian of a child whom you believe has disclosed personal information to us, please contact us at info@activecampaign.com so that we may delete and remove such child’s information from our systems

**Children Between the Ages of 13 and 18**

We recommend that minors who are 13 through 18 years of age seek parental permission before sending information about themselves to anyone over the Internet.

**Choice of Law**

Any disputes arising between you and ActiveCampaign regarding this Privacy Policy shall be governed by the laws of the State of Illinois without regard to its conflict of law provisions.  You and ActiveCampaign agree to submit to the personal and exclusive jurisdiction in the courts located within the county of Chicago, Illinois.  You hereby waive any argument that any such court does not have jurisdiction over you or that such dispute or venue in any such court is not appropriate or convenient.  ActiveCampaign will be entitled to recover its court costs and reasonable attorneys’ fees and expenses incurred if it successfully proves your violation of any term of this Privacy Policy.

**Contact Us**

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us at info@activecampaign.com.

Last Modified:  August 6, 2012
